In this video, we are going to execute some calls to printf using
在本视频中，我们将使用
a variety of format specifiers so you can see how to print types other than int.
各种格式说明符对 printf 执行一些调用，这样你就可以看到如何打印 int 以外的类型。
First, we initialize a char letter to be G and int negNumber to be -1,
首先，我们将字符字母初始化为 G，int negNumber 初始化为 -1，将
and an unsigned int age to be 33.
无符号整数初始化为 33。
Next, we come to a print statement.
接下来，我们来看一份印刷声明。
Printf will look for any format specifiers and in this case,
Printf 将查找任何格式说明符，在本例中，
it has a %c telling printf to look at the next argument and format it as a character.
它有一个 %c 告诉 printf 查看下一个参数并将其格式化为字符。
It prints, my name begins with G. The next statement has
它会打印，我的名字以 G 开头。下一条语句有
the familiar %d and we've seen before that it will print negNumber as a decimal integer.
熟悉的 %d，我们之前已经看到它会将 negNumber 打印为十进制整数。
The next statement prints the value of age as a decimal integer,
下一个语句将 age 的值打印为十进制整数，
but the next statement uses
但下一个语句使用
the %o format specifier telling printf to print the value of age in octal or base eight.
%o 格式说明符告诉 printf 以八进制或八进制打印年龄的值。
The final statement has a %x telling printf to
最后一条语句有一个 %x 告诉 printf 将
print the value of age as a hexadecimal or base 16 integer.
age 的值打印为十六进制或以 16 为基数的整数。
What if we change things around a bit and use
如果我们稍微改变一下然后使用
format specifiers that seems strange for the types of data we are passing it?
对于我们传递的数据类型来说看起来很奇怪的格式说明符，该怎么办？
We start the same way,
我们以同样的方式开始，
but now our print statement uses %d to format letter. What will happen?
但是现在我们的打印语句使用 %d 来格式化信件。会发生什么？
Well, remember that everything is a number.
好吧，请记住，一切都是数字。
Letter actually has a numerical value which is 71.
字母的数值实际上是 71。
This numerical value is what actually gets passed to printf.
这个数值实际上是传递给 printf 的值。
Printf has no idea that the 71 value
Printf 不知道
it receives is originally from a char so it just prints 71.
它收到的 71 值最初来自一个字符，所以它只打印 71。
Next, we print negNumber which is -1 as a hexadecimal number.
接下来，我们将为 -1 的 negNumber 打印为十六进制数。
If you work out how negative one is represented with a 32-bit signed integer,
如果你计算出 32 位有符号整数如何表示负数，
you will find the hex value is ffffffff.
你会发现十六进制值是 fffffffff。
Our next statement uses %u which formats an integer as an unsigned decimal number.
我们的下一个语句使用 %u，它将整数格式化为无符号的十进制数。
But we are passing in negNumber,
但是我们正在传递 negNumber，
so what will happen?
那么会发生什么？
Remember that everything is just a bunch of bits to the computer.
请记住，对于计算机来说，一切都只是一堆碎片。
If you take the binary representation of -1,
如果你取-1的二进制表示形式，
which is 32 ones,
也就是32个一，
and interpret it as an unsigned 32-bit integer,
然后将其解释为一个无符号的32位整数，
you get the largest possible 32-bit unsigned integer,
你就会得到可能的最大32位无符号整数，约
which is about 4.2 billion.
为42亿。
Our last print statement uses %c to format the integer age. What happens here?
我们的最后一个打印语句使用 %c 来格式化整数年龄。这里会发生什么？
Well again, everything is just a number,
再说一遍，一切都只是一个数字，
so printf will print out the character whose numeric representation is 33,
所以 printf 将打印出数字表示形式为 33 的字符，
which is the exclamation mark character.
即感叹号字符。
What if we work with floating point numbers instead?
如果我们改用浮点数呢？
Here are some more printf calls that use floats and doubles.
以下是更多使用浮点数和双精度数的 printf 调用。
p1 is a float,
p1 是浮点数，
3.141592, and p2 is a double that contains more digits of pi.
3.141592，p2 是包含更多位数 pi 的双精度。
The first call to printf uses
对 printf
the %f format specifier to print p1 as a floating point number.
的第一次调用使用 %f 格式说明符将 p1 打印为浮点数。
The next call has a %e,
下一个调用有一个 %e，
which means print p1 in scientific notation.
这意味着用科学计数法打印 p1。
Note the e+00, which means times ten to the zeroth power or times one.
请注意 e+00，这意味着乘以零次方或乘以一。
If we were to print 100 pi using scientific notation,
如果我们使用科学计数法打印 100 pi，则
we would get e+02 for times 10 to the second power.
将乘以 10 的次方得到 e+02。
Next, we have the format specifier %.10f.
接下来，我们有格式说明符 %.10f。
The .10 between the percent and the f means to print 10 decimal places.
百分比和 f 之间的.10 表示打印 10 位小数。
When we do this, we get a slightly odd answer.
当我们这样做时，我们会得到一个有点奇怪的答案。
Where did this 0258 come from?
这个 0258 是从哪里来的？
This comes from the fact that floating point numbers
这源于这样一个事实，即浮点数
can't represent every possible number precisely.
无法精确地表示所有可能的数字。
C rounded 3.141592 to
C 在
when it performed the initialization of p1.
执行 p1 的初始化时将 3.141592 四舍五入到最接近的可表示浮点数。
When we print p1, it converts that number
当我们打印 p1 时，它会将
which is actually stored in p1 to a decimal representation.
实际存储在 p1 中的数字转换为十进制表示形式。
If that is confusing,
如果这令人困惑，
it is okay for now since we will not do much with floating point.
那么现在还可以，因为我们不会对浮点进行太多处理。
But if you find yourself writing real programs with floating point,
但是，如果你发现自己用浮点写真实的程序，
you need to understand how all of this works to avoid subtle and dangerous problems.
你需要了解所有这些是如何工作的，以避免出现微妙和危险的问题。
Next, we print p2 with the default formatting for a double,
接下来，我们使用默认的双
which prints six digits after the decimal,
精度格式打印 p2，即在小数点后打印六位数字，将
rounding the last one.
最后一个数字四舍五入。
Our next printf prints p2 with 10 digits after the decimal.
我们的下一个 printf 打印的是小数点后面有 10 位数的 p2。
Here, they are all what we expect.
在这里，它们都是我们所期望的。
Why is this different?
这有什么不同？
Doubles can represent more numbers more precisely than floats can,
双数可以比浮点数更精确地表示更多的数字，
so the inaccuracies of representing this number do not appear in these 10 digits.
因此表示这个数字的不准确之处不会出现在这 10 位数字中。